[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
Okay, so that's one way to retrieve a document of interest.
好的 以上是检索文件的其中一种方法
Just take all articles out there, scan over them, and
只需要收集所有的文章 快速浏览它们
find the one that's most similar according to the metric that we define.
并且找出最符合我们标准的那一个
But another thing we might be interested in doing is clustering documents that
但是我们还有可能对其他的问题感兴趣
are related, so for example.
比如说对相关联的文件进行聚类
You might have a whole bunch of articles about sports or world news or
你可能有一堆关于体育或者世界新闻或者其他什么的文章
different things like this, and if we can structure our corpus in this way,
而如果我们能用这种方法来构建我们的语料库
if a person is reading an article that's about sports,
那当有人读到一篇关于体育的文章时
then we can very quickly search over all the other articles about sports,
我们就可以迅速查找所有其它关于体育的文章
instead of looking at every article that's out there in the entire corpus.
而不需要翻遍语料库里所有的文章
But the challenge here is the fact that these articles aren't going to have
然而现在的挑战在于
labels.
不是所有的文章都已经被标记好
It's not gonna be like the New York Times, where you go and
不像读纽约时报那样 你看到一篇文章
somebody says, this is an education article.
就已经有人告诉你 这是一篇教育类的文章
Okay, and all we have are articles, and what we like to do, or
好的 现在我们只有一些文章和我们打算做的分析
discover these underlying groups of articles.
或者我们打算找到这些文章的潜在分类方法
Okay, so the goal is to discover these groups or clusters of related articles,
好的 所以我们的目标是对这些相关文章进行分组或者聚类
and like I mentioned, one might represent a set of articles like sports, and
像我之前讲的那样 我们可以把一组文章描述为体育类
another one a set of articles about world news.
而把另一组文章定义为世界新闻类
For the time being, let's actually assume that someone provides us with labels,
就目前来说 我们假定已经有人给我们提供了标签
so, somebody goes through and reads every article or
也就是说 有人通读了每一篇文章
at least a large sub-set of articles in our corpus and labels them and
或者至少浏览了我们语料库中的大部分文章 并且给他们一一标上标签
says, okay, these articles, these are all about sports.
然后说 好的 在这些文章里 这一部分全部是关于体育的
And these ones, these are about world news.
那这一部分呢 这些是关于世界新闻的
And these about entertainment.
而这些是娱乐版
And these ones are about science.
还有这些是科学版
So we have some set of articles that have labels associated with them.
所以我们有一组被标记好的文章
Well, in this case, when we have our query article and we like to
那么 在这种情况下 当我们拿出我们的待查询的文章
sign it to a cluster, this ends up being just a multi-class classification problem.
并打算把它放入一个分类中的时候 这根本上不过是一个多元分类问题
Because the question is just, here is my query article,
因为问题就是 现在我有一个待处理的文章
I don't know the label associated with it, and I have a bunch of label document.
我不知道改把它标记成什么 然后我有一堆标记好的文件
I have the labels world news, science, sports, entertainment, technology,
我有一系列的标签 像世界新闻啦 科学啦 体育啦 娱乐啦 还有科技啦
and I just wanna classify which class this article belongs to, okay?
而我不过是想看看这篇文章属于哪个分类 好吗
So this is the question.
那么现在问题来了
It's just a multi class classification problem.
这真的就只是一个多元分类问题
So if that were the case, that would be an example of a supervise learning problem.
所以如果是这种情况的话 我们面对的其实是一例监督学习问题
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community